

Evgeniy Babiychuk

Expert React and React Native Developer

SUMMARY

I am a web and mobile developer with 8 years of experience, specializing in React and React Native. Throughout my career, I have successfully created and enhanced numerous web and mobile apps, working across various industries including ecommerce, social media platforms, blockchain, data visualizations, and SaaS projects. I am always eager to explore new technologies and seek out fresh opportunities in this field. Before starting work on a project. I think

ahead how it should be in the end, introducing myself as a consumer of the project. I excel at working collaboratively to solve complex problems and enjoy being part of a team.

EDUCATION

2015-2017

Master's degree in Software Engineering

National Aviation University (Institute Of Computer Information Technologies) - full-time education

2008 - 2012

Software Development - Junior Specialist

College Of Information Technology And Land Management

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jun 2023 - Feb 2024

Frontend Developer

Sixpack Motors

Replacement and accessories for all US cars, car import, sales, mfk, workshop, preparation, tuning

My Role:

I've built the frontend o this website -

https://www.sixpackmotors.ch/

Required skills: React, NextJS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, LESS, SASS

Feb 2023 - Dec 2023

Full Stack Developer

SimpleShowing

simpleshowing is the new way to buy or sell a home. Users can buy with their team of licensed agents, and save up to \$15,000. sell for only a 1% listing fee.

My Role:

I've built both frontend and backend of the website -

https://www.simpleshowing.com/

Required skills: React, NextJS, Material UI, Node.JS, ExpressJS

Mar 2022 - Apr 2023

Full Stack Developer

SAYU

golf equipment online from complete golfer, huge savings on all the top brands at lowest uk price guaranteed plus free next day uk delivery.

My Role:

I've built both frontend and backend of the website -

https://www.completegolfer.co.uk/

Azure

Required skills: Javascrpit, Co-PHP

Oct 2021 - Feb 2022

Frontend Developer

IFIT

Amazing workout webapp!

Its service provides interactive personal training with on-demand fitness classes – treadmill, cycling, abs, and more.

My Role:

I've participated in enhancing the User interface and optimizing the codebase for this webapp - https://www.ifit.com/

Required skills: React, NextJS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Styled-components

June 2020 - August 2021

Frontend Developer

Merehead

Merehead is an outsourcing company, that mainly focuses on developing fintech and blockchain solutions.

My Role:

- 1. Developing user-facing features using React.js
- -Setup applications from scratch.
- -Building reusable components and front-end libraries for future use
- -Translating designs and wireframes into high-quality code
- -Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers
- -Deploying code to staging/production
- 2. Participation in the development of 6 projects in the direction of marketplace, blockchain, social network project, and a small private site

Required skills: Typescript, React, React-router, Redux, Redux-Thunk, Redux-Saga, Git, ESlint, WebSocket, Restful APIs, Postman, React Hooks, Axios, Styled Components, Stripe, i18next

July 2019 - January 2020

Frontend Developer

Jerelia

Jerelia is a large-scale network company that provides natural cosmetics, innovative eco-cleaning products for the home, accessories, vitamins, complex body cleansing programs, herbal preparations for health from Ukraine.

My Role:

I've built a shopping mall website for this company. -

https://jerelia.com/

My role is to build the frontend and integrate backend. **Required skills:** ReactJS, NodeJS

Figma

September 2016 - June 2017

Frontend Developer

Energorynok

Energorynok is a state-owned company founded in 2000 by the state in person of the Cabinet of Ministers of Ukraine and is a Party to the Agreement between the members of the Wholesale Electricity Market of Ukraine.

My Role:

I've built 2 website for this company

https://www.oree.com.ua/

https://www.gpee.com.ua/

Required skills: Javascript, Google map service, iCheck, ChartJS, Oracle DB, jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap

June 2017 - March 2019

Frontend Developer

Ukravtonomgaz

Ukravtonomgaz is a large-scale Ukrainian group operating in the liquefied gas market.

My Role:

I've participated in building the frontend of this website -

https://ukravtonomgaz.ua/

Required skills: Javascript, Flex, Twig, Gulp, PostgreSQL, jQuery slick-slider, Drupal CMS

Apr 2019 - Jan 2020

React Native Mobile Developer

Hipcamp

Travel Booking application.

My Role:

- -build the Mobile UI
- -Enhance filtering function
- -Enhance Map service

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

React Native Mobile Developer

Reelfolio

Reelfolio is the online social networking platform for the filmmakers.

My Role:

- -Developing mobile UI with React Native framework
- -Developing backend with NodeJS
- -Integrate backend and implement unit test
- -Deploying code to staging.production

React Native Mobile Developer

Marine snow

Marine snow is the premier global hall of songs, curated and contextualized.

My Role:

- -Mobile UI build of the Discovery part and onboarding logic implementation
- -Create the music orbs by using the lottie json
- -Optimize the codebase to reduce the memory and CPU usage
- -Gamification of the music play logic
- -Integrate backend api and unit test